[girl] I hate television.
Gives me headaches.
[TV playing indistinctly]
You know. I heard there's so many
magnetic waves traveling through the air
because of TV and telephones
that we're losing like 10 times as many
brain cells as we're supposed to.
Like. all the molecules in our heads
are all unstable
and all the companies know about it but
they're not doing anything about it.
It's a big conspiracy.
[sighs] You can pick something.
I don't care.
[TV playing indistinctly]
You have any idea how many electro-waves
are traveling through our head
every second?
I got a better one.
Have you heard about this videotape
that kills you when you watch it?
What kinda tape?
A tape. A regular tape.
People rent it. I don't know.
You start to play it and
it's like somebody's nightmare.
Then suddenly. this woman comes on.
smiling at you. right?
Seeing you through the screen.
And as soon as it's over.
your phone rings.
Someone knows you've watched it.
And what they say is.
"You will die in seven days."
And exactly seven days later...
[whispers] Who told you that?
-Somebody from Revere. I don't--
-Who told you?
What's your problem?
[whispers] I've watched it.
[sighs] It's a story. Katie.
No. me and Josh. we saw it last weekend.
-I thought you were with your parents.
-1-I wanted to tell you.
-You were with Josh all weekend?
-Some of his friends got--got this place
up in the mountains.
They were trying to record
a football game. [stammers]
-I guess the reception was so bad--
-What are you talking about?
[Katie] Listen to me!
When we played the tape.
the game wasn't there. It was...
What? What was it?
It was something else.
[scoffs lightly] We thought it was
some kind of sick joke.
And then the phone rang.
It was a week ago.
A week ago tonight.
[chuckles weakly]
You're just trying to scare me.
[gagging]
[Katie gasps]
-[gagging. gasping]
-Oh. my God. Katie. Are you okay? What--
-[gagging. groaning]
-Katie.
-[laughing]
-You freak!
-You totally fell for it.
-No.
So. did you guys. you know. do anything?
Like what?
Oh. my God. you totally did!
You a ho! Tell me now!
-No!
-[both laughing]
[phone rings]
[gasps]
[ominous music]
[clock ticking]
[phone continues ringing]
There really is a tape.
This is so lame.
Embry residence.
Hello?
Hi. Mom.
Ugh!
Yeah. that was Becca.
My mom says hi. she's glad you're here.
[whispers]
Ask her where she keeps her Vicodin.
Yeah. we're about to go to sleep.
Okay. Yeah. I will.
Okay. okay. yeah. yeah. I will.
No. I won't.
Bye. Mom.
[phone beeps]
[static crackling]
[rain pattering]
Becca. quit being a bitch.
Where's the remote?
[static stops]
[static crackling]
Becca. quit it!
[static stops]
[ominous music]
[gasps]
[panting]
[ominous music]
Becca. can you hear me?
[low buzzing]
[ominous music]
[breathing heavily]
[high-pitched ringing]
[static crackling]
[crayon scratching softly]
[door opens in distance]
[indistinct shouting in distance]
[woman] I am being objective.
Listen. Harvey. you punctilious prick.
you touch my column.
and I'm coming down there
and poking your eye out
with that little red pencil
you like so much.
Harvey?
[sighs] Shit!
Hey.
Sorry I'm late.
No worries.
I'll wait in the car.
Have you got a moment. Ms. Keller?
Um. sure.
Call me Rachel.
-Please. sit down.
He certainly is very independent.
isn't he?
Yeah. he sure is.
I never have to tell him to do anything.
Well. if that's a problem. you'd be
the first teacher in history to say so.
-Ms. Keller...
-Rachel.
I know that Aidan recently lost
his cousin--
Yes. and I'm doing what I can to find him
some good daycare. it's just--
Oh. no. that's not what I meant.
By all means. take your time.
I know they were very close.
-Yeah.
-Aidan and his cousin.
They spent a few nights a week together.
Did he talk to you about her death?
Well. like you said.
he's not the talkative type.
That doesn't mean he has nothing to say.
He knows I'm there.
[teacher] Yes. I'm sure he does.
But he may expressing himself in...
other ways.
I'd like to show you something.
[Rachel] That's his cousin.
It's Katie.
Ms. Keller...
I'm bothered by these drawings.
Listen. I-I appreciate your concern.
but my son lost his best friend
three nights ago.
He's just trying to deal with it.
Yes. I understand. but these pictures--
Are Aidan's way of working it out.
Of expressing himself. like you said.
He'll be okay.
You say she died three nights ago.
Yeah. that's right.
Aidan drew these last week.
[somber music]
What?
Nothing.
Should we read something?
I'm kinda tired.
Okay.
Sweet dreams.
Don't have enough time.
Oh. honey. I know I've been working a lot.
And I'm sorry but I promise you.
I'm gonna make it up to you.
I'm not talking about that.
I'm talking about time before we die.
You have lots of time.
So you know when I'm going to die?
[Rachel] No.
No one does.
But I know
you don't have to worry about it.
Katie knew.
She told me.
Katie told you she was gonna die?
[Aidan]
She said she didn't have enough time.
Goodnight. Rachel.
[rain pattering]
[closet door rattling]
[Rachel] Oh. shit. [grunting]
Aidan!
Goddammit.
Honey!
Have you seen my black dress?
Aidan?
Have you seen my black...
dress.
[Aidan] It's a little wrinkled.
It's fine.
[somber music]
[music continues]
[softly] Kids don't have strokes.
Unless they're on drugs.
So then why the closed coffin?
[Rachel] Ruthie...
I'm so sorry.
[Ruth sniffles]
You all right. Dave?
Yeah. I'm fine.
How are you?
[Ruth] He sleeps all day.
Doesn't move.
It's too much for him.
Doesn't make any sense. Rachel.
I spent four hours on the Internet
and I couldn't find one single case of
a 16-year-old girl's heart just stopping.
I spoke to three different doctors
and not one of them could tell me
exactly what happened to my daughter.
She was close with you.
And Aidan.
She confided in you.
Yeah. but she never said anything.
Nothing that would explain what happened.
You could find out.
It's what you do.
Isn't it? Ask questions?
Rachel. please.
I saw her face.
[high-pitched ringing]
-[indistinct chattering]
-[girl] I knew Becca.
I mean. she was a little intense.
but she wasn't crazy.
They don't put you in booties
and a straight jacket
if you're just freaked out.
Something scared the shit out of her.
Hi.
So who's in the mental hospital?
Becca. Katie's friend.
-Oh right. she was the one who was--
-...there
when it happened.
So what do you think
they were doing up there?
[exhales]
[Rachel] Oh. thanks.
I remember I was that age.
me and my girlfriend used to
sneak up to my room. get high.
-Do you think maybe she was into--
-[boy] It's not about that.
It's about the tape.
Kellen. don't even.
What tape?
The one that kills you when you watch it.
Oh. please.
What was on the tape?
I haven't seen it. obviously.
[Rachel]
But Katie told you she saw this tape.
Not Katie. I heard it from her boy--
You heard it from who?
She was dating this guy. Josh.
He goes to Revere.
It was kind of a secret.
Kind of?
Well. where is he? Josh. is he here?
[Kellen] Josh is dead.
[Rachel] What?!
What happened?
Supposedly he killed himself.
The same night that Katie died.
[low dark music]
[music continues]
[ominous whooshing]
[music fades]
[rain pattering]
[Rachel] Aidan.
What are you doing in here?
Come on. We shouldn't be in her room.
It's not her room anymore.
[mysterious music]
[train rattling]
[train whooshing]
[somber music]
[Rachel] 10 PM.
[whispers] 10 PM.
[indistinct chattering]
[phone ringing]
[Rachel] Time of death. Wade.
that's all I wanna know.
Name's Katie Embry.
pull the report and read the time.
Okay. I'll hold.
[man] "Punctilious prick"?
Nice alliteration. huh?
-[man] You're fired.
-No. I'm not.
[man] Yes. You are.
No. I'm not.
I'm cooking too good a story.
What is it?
[Rachel] Yeah. I'm still here.
Tch!
Okay. so what's the time of death?
[mysterious music]
[ominous music]
[music fades]
[bell rings]
-Hi. I was wondering--
-[innkeeper] Pick a card.
Any card.
Go ahead.
Okay. Put it back. [sighs]
Don't let me see it.
That your card?
No.
Damn.
I was wondering if you'd remember someone
from a week ago.
Hm. is there a problem?
It's my niece. she...
sort of ran out on her parents.
No.
I have some photos here.
That's her and her friends.
I think they stayed here a night or so.
[innkeeper] Yeah.
They were in cabin 12.
They didn't pay.
They had a number of complaints.
about the TV. mainly.
The reception's never good here.
That's why we bought tape players
for videos.
[Rachel] Quite a selection.
[scoffs]
Mostly they're hand-me-downs
left by other guests.
Anyway. they didn't pay.
Kids like that sometimes don't.
Miss?
You know. I'm kind of tired. I'm thinking
I might take a nap before I drive back.
I'll take cabin 12.
Hey.
This is your card. right?
That's it!
[ominous music]
[music fades]
[static buzzing]
[eerie music]
[high-pitched ringing]
[low rumbling]
[eerie music]
[squelching]
[high-pitched ringing]
[wet squelching]
[ringing continues]
[eerie music]
[static buzzing]
[ringing fades]
[waves rushing softly]
[low rumbling]
[eerie music]
[static buzzing]
[ominous whooshing]
[static continues buzzing]
[static stops]
[phone ringing]
[gasps]
-[girl] Seven days.
-[exhales shakily]
[ominous music]
[music intensifies]
[rain pattering]
[music fades]
I'm going to school.
[ominous music]
[door closes]
[rain pouring]
[indistinct chattering]
[Rachel] What do you think?
[man] It's a pretty cool effect.
What does this have to do with the tape?
Take my picture.
[camera whirring]
Are you gonna look at me at least?
[camera beeps]
This the same camera?
No. Scan the rest.
[camera beeping]
[Rachel] So? What do you think?
I don't--look. I thought you said
this was about a tape.
I'm thinking maybe you shouldn't see it.
-[chuckles]
-No. I should know more about it first.
Well. isn't that why I'm here?
So you can benefit from my wisdom.
Four kids are dead. Noah.
Not from watching a videotape.
Come on. show it to me.
[static buzzing]
[eerie music]
[high-pitched ringing]
[low rumbling]
[eerie music]
[maniacal laughter]
[dramatic cartoon music playing]
[wistful music]
[TVs playing indistinctly]
[music continues]
[door sliding]
[Noah] Roll credits.
It was very student film.
I'm sure it's a lot scarier at night.
[phone ringing]
You gonna get that?
[phone continues ringing]
[ringing stops]
So. you been working a lot?
I'm not tired. Noah.
-Okay.
-That tape didn't scare you?
No. not really. Sorry.
Four people are dead.
-Yeah. but like I said. not from--
-Four people who watched it.
-Well. we watched it. we're hangin'.
-It...
takes a week.
Right.
You know. I'm just gonna go downtown.
I gotta pick up some cameras
from this guy.
and then I gotta prep this thing
that I may end up doing next week.
Noah.
Would you say that I'm gullible?
-No.
-Easily rattled?
Definitely not.
I mean. a little highly-strung. maybe.
-You ain't much of a dresser.
-Who made it?
Where'd it come from?
All right. Make me a copy.
I'll see what I can do.
Thanks.
[door shuts]
[mysterious music]
[indistinct chattering]
[phone ringing]
[eerie music]
[high-pitched ringing]
[mysterious music]
[machine whirring. clicking]
[music continues]
[elevator rumbling]
[low rumbling]
You sure this is a copy?
Yeah. why?
The numbers are all screwed up.
Same problem got copied. I guess.
That's impossible.
The numbers are the control track.
They're put on the tape
whenever it's recorded
which means. theoretically.
there shouldn't be any images.
Hey. Noah. can you pretend for one minute
that I don't read Video Geek magazine?
Okay. when you record a tape.
the makeup of the tracks
is like a signature
for whatever did the recording
like a camcorder. VCR. whatever.
So the control track can tell us
where it came from.
To not have one.
I mean. that's like being born
without fingerprints.
Then how did this get recorded?
I don't know.
But I'm gonna find out.
All right. take a look.
You should be able to see the camera
right here in the reflection.
The angle's straight on. but you don't.
[Rachel] Hm. What's that?
Looks like she's walking away.
whoever she is.
No. I mean up there at the top.
[Noah] Oh no. that's just the tracking.
I can fix that.
Whoops. Sorry.
Wait. go back.
There's something there.
-[Noah] Oh. you're right.
-There's more picture.
[Noah] Hold on.
I'm gonna stretch the alignment.
-Yeah. it's working.
-Yeah. it won't go any further.
-Okay. keep going.
-[Noah] It won't go any--
-No. no. no. let me do it. Come on.
-It won't go any further.
-[Rachel] Let me do it!
-Shit!
[Rachel] Ah...
[both chuckle]
Hey. Noah. I picked up the cameras.
-They're in really good shape.
-[door shuts]
Did you see the reprints I did
of that Guatemala stuff?
'Cause they came out kinda...
over-exposed.
You working?
This is a friend. Rachel Keller.
She writes for the PI.
Rachel. this is Beth. my assistant.
[Beth] Well. I prefer "partner in crime.”
She's a journalism student
at Kirkland. actually.
[Beth] Well. I'll stay outta your way.
I'm not even here.
Rachel is researching a story.
It's this video hoax.
It's sort of interesting.
So you know video.
Why don't you come take a look
at this thing with the tracking?
[Rachel] You know. I'm late.
I really should go.
-Yeah. but why are you taking--
- I gotta go.
Good to meet you.
[elevator rumbling]
-You're takin' the tape?
-I didn't want her to see it.
Whoa. you don't want her to see.
what about me seeing it?
You had no problem showing it to me.
I did have a problem.
-You're angry.
-I'm not angry.
-Oh. no. what are you then?
-In a hurry.
[sighs] Look. I'm sorry.
but I'm not gonna get all worked up
over some high school rumor.
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking this is the part
where I say you're a flake
who never finishes anything.
Then you say I'm an obsessive bitch
who needs to lighten up.
Then I storm out all pissed off.
kicking myself for ever thinking
that you could just...
grow up.
So why don't we just
cut to that part right now and
save ourselves a lot of grief?
All right. Bye.
[mysterious music]
Watch out. missy. Bad luck.
You don't need that.
[low rumbling]
[wheel squeaking]
[audience clapping on TV]
[indistinct chattering on TV]
[nurse] Becca?
Becca.
We're almost there.
[TV continues playing indistinctly]
[Rachel]
Do you remember anything about that night?
That night with Katie?
Do you remember...how she died?
Becca?
She told you about a videotape.
didn't she?
[mysterious music]
She was afraid. wasn't she?
Something was happening to her.
Becca.
How did she die?
Please.
I need to know.
And you will.
She'll show you.
[Rachel] Who?
Who will show me?
Not now.
[music building]
Four days.
-[machine whirring]
-[woman] Yeah. well. your home VCRs.
they'll give you a tracking window.
but they won't let you stretch it.
There's no point. really.
unless you're talking restoration.
Archives'll come in here with
these crummy old tapes sometimes.
tracks totally shot.
servos can't line 'em up.
Big box here's a warhorse. totally analog.
She'll read to the very edge of your tape.
Just don't force her
or she'll get pissy with you.
Your tracking. your monitor.
your printer. if you need it.
So. uh. what are we watchin'?
Home movies or something?
I'd really rather watch it alone.
Really.
Whatever.
[mysterious music]
[machine whirring]
Come on.
[whirring faster]
[intriguing music]
Lighthouse.
[powering down]
Shit.
Hello?
Somebody?
[whirring]
[mysterious music]
[ominous music]
[buzzing]
Something you needed help with?
Hey. you--you got a...uh...
[low rumbling]
[man]
Well. that seems to be the lot of it.
Thank you.
[mysterious music]
[intriguing music]
"Moesko Island."
[music continues]
[low rumbling]
"Anna Morgan."
[music continues]
Oh. my God.
[papers rustling]
[tense music]
"Mysterious Sickness
Strikes Morgan Ranch Horses."
"Investigators search for answers
after second horse drowning."
[low rumbling]
[mysterious music]
[whispers] Anna Morgan.
"Horses Recovering
After Breeder's Suicide."
"Suffered from hallucinations."
"Eola County Psychiatric..."
What happened to you. Anna?
[ominous music]
[low rumbling]
Pack of Double Lights.
Thanks. Lani.
-[register beeps]
-15.33.
You're gonna die.
My cousin was two packs a day.
Used the patch. never looked back.
All right. well. I'll keep that in mind.
Have a nice day.
You too.
[ominous music]
[low rumbling]
[ominous whooshing]
[static buzzing]
[gasps. shouts]
-[pants. chuckles] Hi.
-Relax.
-Sorry I'm late.
-[groans. clears throat]
No. no problem.
Everything okay?
[babysitter] Oh. yeah. he was an angel.
I-I went in to tell him
that it was bedtime.
and he was already under the covers
and then he read me a bedtime story.
Um. [clears throat]
he learned the word "conundrum.”
-Really?
-Yeah. and then he drew my picture.
Well. here you go.
Oh.
-[Rachel] Thanks.
-Sure.
[gentle music]
[Rachel] Hey. Ruthie. it's me. I'm sorry
to call so late but I need a favor.
I have to go upstate to do a story and
I need you to watch Aidan for me.
[Ruth] Oh. Rachel. I don't know.
How long will you be gone?
It's just for two days. I promise.
[spits. coughs]
-[Ruth] Rachel. are you there?
-[coughs] Hold on. I just--
[coughs] Sorry. [coughing]
-[coughing]
-[Ruth] Rachel?
-Is this about Katie?
-[continues coughing]
[gagging. gasping]
[coughing. retching]
[low ominous music]
[gasps. coughs]
[gagging]
[coughs. gasps]
Ruthie...
[ominous music]
[breathing shakily]
Aidan?
[music continues]
[voice screaming]
[eerie music]
[gasping. panting]
[exhales heavily]
[eerie music]
[high-pitched ringing]
[low rumbling]
[static buzzing]
[screams] No!
Don't! [panting]
Why. baby. why? Why?!
I couldn't sleep.
[somber music]
[exhales heavily]
Who is she. Rachel?
[phone ringing]
[gasps]
[phone rings]
Leave him alone!
-[Noah] Rachel?
-[exhales sharply]
[gasps] Noah.
[Noah] Li--listen to me. Rachel.
I need to talk to you. okay? I...
I believe you.
Rachel. you there?
[crying]
He watched the tape.
Who. who watched it?
Our son.
[ominous music]
[low rumbling]
You took my picture.
I've seen you.
When I'm in the yard at school.
You were there.
You wish I was around more?
No.
You wanna be around more?
-Rachel and I were--
-Young.
Mom's told me that story.
The thing is...
I don't think I'd make a good father.
Maybe it was because my own was...
such a...disappointment.
Thing is. I don't want
anyone else to do it. either.
Be your father.
It's a conundrum.
[chuckles]
Yeah. it is.
[mysterious music]
[somber music]
Time to go. mister.
[Aidan] I'm not finished.
Noah said to make one for you.
[mysterious music]
[Rachel] You could almost draw a line
through her life.
On one side there's this happy woman
who spends her time with her husband.
riding horses. everything sheltered.
protected. and comfortable.
Her face. there's light. There's pride.
And then one day. something happens
and she takes this hard corner
and the light goes out.
And then she ends up
at Eola County Psychiatric
all alone.
[Noah] What happened to her?
[Rachel] I don't know yet. but I think
it has something to do with the horses.
[Noah] I think we should
go to the island together.
[Rachel] It's Tuesday. Noah.
I only have one day left.
I need you to go to the hospital and
find out as much as you can about Anna.
The images on the tape
were leading somewhere.
Katie saw them all too.
I think...
before you die. you see the ring.
[rain pouring]
[indistinct announcement over PA]
Shit.
Hey. Rach! Wait!
[bell ringing]
[mysterious music]
Daughter?
[ominous music]
-[horse snuffling]
-Hm.
Hey. you.
-[horse snorts]
-Oh.
It's okay. I'm not gonna hurt you.
-Yeah.
-[shorts]
-[neighs]
-[Rachel] Easy. boy.
[mysterious music]
That's good.
[horse snorting. neighing wildly]
[tense music]
-[metal creaking]
-Hey. boy.
-[snorting]
-[Rachel] I'm not gonna hurt you.
[snorting]
[Rachel] Oh. God.
[neighs]
-[eerie whooshing]
-It's okay. calm down.
[whinnying]
[metal clanging]
[dramatic music]
Somebody!
[neighs]
[banging]
[neighing wildly]
Jesus Christ.
-[intense music]
-Somebody help!
[both grunting]
Daddy. my horse!
[man] Whoa. whoa. whoa!
-[horse neighing]
-[man] He's going out!
[man 2] Over here!
-[neighs]
-[man] Whoa. whoa. whoa. easy.
-[music continues]
-[man] come on.
[snorting]
-[man 2] Watch it. watch it!
-[neighing wildly]
No! Down. no!
[indistinct shouting]
[horse snorting]
[banging]
[horse neighing]
[dramatic music]
[screaming]
[foghorn blows]
[indistinct chattering]
I need to see the records
for a patient named Anna Morgan.
Are you a relative?
Well. no.
I'm sorry. sir.
We're a mental health facility.
Our records are private.
Well. she's been dead 24 years.
I don't think she'll mind.
I'm sorry. It's impossible.
Look...
I've seen 'em before.
I've been up there.
[man] Nice try.
The record rooms are downstairs. guy.
[scoffs]
You win.
[grunting]
Jerkoff.
[ominous music]
[fly buzzing]
You in here. Anna?
[tense mysterious music]
[engine rumbling]
[engine revving]
[low ominous music]
Hello?
[low rumbling]
[music continues]
[hammer tapping in distance]
Excuse me. Mr. Morgan.
I was wondering
if you'd have a moment to speak with me.
My name's Rachel Keller.
I'm a writer with the Seattle PI.
You wanna know about the horses.
I didn't mean to...it's just. I wasn't
able to find a number to reach you.
Every now and then. a writer comes along.
heard about what happened.
What's left to write about. though?
I don't know.
[Rachel]
I was hoping you had just a few minutes.
Well. work never ends around here. really.
But I guess I got a few.
So. what is it you're writing. miss?
My horses in general or
just those that go strange?
[Rachel]
I read you had to put so many down.
Most put themselves down.
They drowned.
How'd they get out?
Just broke through the fences
and ran to the shore.
[Rachel] So they went crazy.
It would seem so. yes.
Or maybe they just sense things
before we do.
So where are your horses now?
I don't breed anymore.
I guess you wouldn't.
Not after what happened.
That must have been hard.
On both of you.
You and your wife.
[low rumbling]
I'm sorry. miss. what's your name again?
-Rachel.
-Well. Rachel.
you wanna tell me
what's really on your mind?
Do you know what this is?
I think it's a message. From your wife.
Anna's on this tape.
She's right there in that room.
You can see the lighthouse. the horses.
[unnerving music]
Where did you get that?
Shelter Mountain Inn.
Is that the only one?
I made a copy.
I got a lot of work to do today.
Lot of acres out there.
Minute I think I'm done with one thing...
another thing needs fixing.
You don't wanna see this tape?
You're not even curious?
Curious?
No. I don't think so.
-Mr. Morgan.
-I can't help you.
Where's your daughter?
-Maybe she could help--
-I don't have a daughter.
Excuse me?
What is it with reporters?
You take one person's tragedy
and force the world to experience it.
spread it like sickness.
-Mr. Morgan. I--
-Tell me. miss.
What is it you think you know?
Then leave it alone.
[somber music]
[music continues]
[banging]
Anna.
"Anna Morgan's...
hallucinations"?
What's wrong with you?
"'65 conceived.
'65 miscarriage. '66 conceived.
'66 miscarriage."
Christ. she wouldn't give up.
[low rumbling]
[papers rustle. thud]
"Sessions terminated at father's request.
See video record SM0015."
[phone ringing]
[crayon scratching]
[Ruth] Aidan?
Aidan. it's your mom!
[ominous whooshing]
[Aidan] Hi. Mom.
Honey. the house you drew for me...
-[Aidan] Uh-huh.
Where did you see it?
Did you see it in your head?
Is that why you drew it?
[Aidan] In my head?
Aidan. why did you draw that house?
[Aidan] Because she told me to.
Who?
Who told you to?
[mysterious music]
The little girl.
[Rachel] She talks to you?
[Aidan] No.
She shows me things.
Did she show you the horses?
She doesn't like it in the barn.
The horses keep her up at night.
So she still lives there?
No.
[whispers] She lives in a dark place now.
[ominous whooshing]
[woman] Getting a little old
to be crabbin' out there. Cal.
Your body's about outlived its warranty.
you know?
-You ain't exactly the catch of the day.
-Oh.
-Let's see you catch one better.
-[Cal] Yeah.
Afternoon. I'm Doctor Grasnik.
I think he was here before me.
Oh. Darby? Darby's always here.
Aren't you. Darby?
He's my son's boy.
Come over on the ferry. did you?
Yes.
Um...
have you lived here long?
Born and raised.
Only doctor on the island.
Then you know the Morgans
and their daughter.
Do you know their daughter?
What's this about?
Look. I'm sorry.
I--I don't know how to say this.
but I'm seeing things in my head.
images. and so is my son.
My son. that...that's why I'm here.
And somehow. I don't know how. but...
it's because of that girl.
Haven't heard anybody say that
in a long time.
[metal creaking]
[Dr. Grasnik]
She wanted a child more than anything
Poor Anna.
They tried hard for years.
but sometimes it's just not meant to be.
Then one winter. they went away.
When they came back. it was with Samara.
Adopted. they said.
Never did say from where.
Said the mother died of complications.
But they had their baby. they had
their horses. everything was fine.
Till Anna started coming to see me.
Said she was suffering visions.
Seeing things.
horrible things.
like they'd been burned inside her.
That it only happened around Samara.
That the girl put them there.
[Rachel] Were you Samara's doctor too?
Was there anything wrong with her?
You mean medically?
I mean whatever you mean.
When Darby there was born.
we knew something wasn't right with him.
But we loved him anyway.
Takes work. you know?
Some people have limits.
So what happened to her?
I referred them to Eola Psychiatric
on the mainland.
I assume she's still there.
You don't know?
How can you not know?
We been through
a lot of hard years out here.
Mean winters.
Small hauls. no fish.
And that was long before the horses.
See. when you live on an island.
you catch a cold. it's everybody's cold.
No offense. ma'am.
but what the hell does that mean??
It means ever since that girl's been gone.
things have been better.
[metal continues creaking]
1978.
Man. we're really going back in time here.
Yeah. lady at reception said
it should still be here.
Should be.
You say
you're the patient's father. right?
Yep. Richard Morgan. that's me.
What is your secret?
-Diet and exercise. man.
-No shit.
Yeah. that's all it takes.
You know. I'm not an idiot.
You try and walk outta here with my file.
and I'll be on you like white on rice.
you understand?
-No. man. I just wanna watch it.
I'm responsible for every file tape
in here.
I have a system.
I don't want anyone disarranging it.
I'd never...disarrange...
Long as we understand each other.
Okay. now I'm mad.
Does it say who--who was the last person
to watch it?
Yeah.
It was you.
Come on. come on.
[tone beeping]
[recording] The mobile unit you called
is not responding
or is outside the covered area.
You piece of shit.
[phone beeping]
[ominous music]
[sighs]
Come on. Rachel.
[insects chirping]
Hello?
Mr. Morgan?
[ominous music]
[ominous whooshing]
[dramatic musical sting]
[gasping]
[somber music]
[man]
This is SM0015. Samara Morgan. hour 14.
Good. Very good.
So what is it that's keeping you awake?
You must sleep sometime.
Do you dream about something?
Samara?
Let's talk about the pictures.
How did you make them?
Samara?
How did you make these pictures?
[Samara] I don't...
make them.
I see them.
And then...
they just...
are.
[man] Samara.
I need you to start
telling me the truth. okay?
[Samara] Can I see my mommy?
[man] No. Samara. not until
we understand what's wrong with you.
[Samara] I love my mommy.
[man] Yes. you do.
But you don't want to hurt her anymore.
now. do you?
You don't wanna hurt anyone.
[Samara] But I do and I'm sorry.
It won't stop.
[man] Well. that's why you're here.
So that I can help you to make it stop.
[Samara] He's going to leave me here.
[man] Who?
[Samara] Daddy.
[man] They just wanna help you.
[Samara] Not Daddy.
[man] Your daddy loves you.
[Samara] Daddy loves the horses.
He wants me to go away.
[man] No. he doesn't.
[Samara] But he doesn't know...
[man] He doesn't know what?
Samara?
[static buzzing]
[dramatic musical sting]
[Rachel grunts]
She's never gonna whisper
in my fuckin' ear ever again!
What did you do to her?!
[low tense music]
[Rachel grunts. pants]
She was your daughter!
[grunts. pants]
You killed Samara. didn't you?!
You killed her and
when your wife found out--
My wife was not supposed to have a child!
[dark music]
[water running]
[Rachel] Mr. Morgan!
-What are you doing?
-[Richard] The whispers...
you could hear them all the time.
At night. in your sleep.
Even the damn horses.
-Mr. Morgan. come out of there.
-[Richard] And those pictures.
Oh. Christ. The things she'd show you.
She's still showing them.
[Richard] And she'll never stop.
You comin' here proves that.
[Rachel] Where is she?
Where is she? Please.
I have to stop her.
If I don't. my son will die!
Oh. yes. He will.
She never sleeps.
Wait. No.
-[screaming] No!
-[electricity crackling. sparking]
[screaming]
No!
-[screaming] No!
-Rachel! Rachel!
-[screaming]
-Shh! Shh! It's all right! Shh!
-[Rachel panting]
-[shushing] It's okay. It's okay.
-It's okay. [shushing]
-[Rachel whimpering]
You're okay. Shh. shh.
-[panting]
-You okay?
[water running]
-[electricity zapping]
-[Noah] Oh. Jesus.
[low mysterious music]
[Aidan] She doesn’t like the barn.
The horses keep her up at night.
She doesn't like the barn.
[Noah] What?
[Rachel] The horses keep her awake.
[gentle somber music]
Samara.
[carousel playing slow. bright music]
[Rachel] He kept her here.
Her mother was going crazy.
Morgan blamed the child.
So he kept her here.
[music stops]
Alone.
Not alone.
[somber music]
Rachel.
There's something in here.
[mysterious music]
It looks like it's etched into the wood.
[Rachel] Or burned.
[music swells]
[music fades. continues]
I've seen this tree before.
[Noah] Yeah. it was on the tape.
No.
I've been there.
[ominous music]
Shelter Mountain.
[low rumbling]
[mysterious music]
[Rachel] The sun came through the leaves.
lit them up like it was on fire.
Right at sunset.
Right when I watched the tape.
That was a week ago.
[sighs]
We're back to where we started from.
Well. something led us here.
the tree. the drawing on the wall.
[Rachel] It doesn't matter.
We're too late.
You have to help him.
What are you talking about?
Aidan.
It's up to you now. just use the time
you have and figure something out.
We're gonna figure this out together
right now!
It's too late. Noah!
Stop it! Okay.
there's a reason that we're here!
-What?
-[Noah] I don't know. okay?
But it's something in this room and I--
I mean. it's in this phone!
It's in this television!
Come on! Call us now. why don't ya?!
[grunts]
[objects clattering]
[Rachel] Noah.
Look.
[gentle mysterious music]
[glass shattering]
[grunting]
[tense music]
[grunting continues]
[dark music]
[Rachel grunts]
[stone scraping]
[Noah] Oh. Jesus.
How far down do you think it goes?
I can't see anything.
[static crackling softly]
[music continues]
You know. we should drop something.
[static buzzing]
[ominous music]
[Noah] You think she's down there?
Shhh...
[creaking]
[dramatic music]
[flies buzzing]
[Rachel groaning]
[Rachel shouts]
[screams]
Rachel!
[music fades]
[water bubbling]
[coughing]
[echoing] Rachel!
[Rachel panting]
[Noah. echoing] Rachel!
I'm here!
I'm all right!
I think.
[Noah]
I'll go find something to get you out!
[Rachel] Hurry!
[low eerie music]
[high-pitched ringing]
[exhales heavily]
[distant bang]
[stone scraping]
Noah?
[ominous music]
[grunting]
Noah?
Noah!
[gasping]
[ominous music]
No!
Oh. [panting]
[music stops]
[panting]
[ominous music]
[screaming]
[Rachel gasping]
[wind whooshes]
[Samara. softly] ♪ Here we go ♪
♪ The world is spinning ♪
♪ When it stops ♪
♪ It's just beginning ♪
[Anna] Isn't it beautiful here. Samara?
So peaceful.
I know things will get better.
[low rumbling]
[breathing shakily]
[softly] All I ever wanted was you.
[dark music]
[low rumbling muted by water]
[gasps]
[panting]
She was still alive.
[muted water splashing. Rachel panting]
[melancholic music]
It's okay now.
It's okay.
[Noah] Rachel!
[Rachel gasping]
Rachel. the sun's set!
The sun has set! It's past sunset.
Do you hear me?
It's past sunset!
[music continues]
Rachel!
Rachel. are you there?
I'm here.
[somber music]
[indistinct chattering]
[Noah] They're gonna bury her next week.
It's over.
You okay?
She wanted that child
more than anything in the world.
How could she have done that?
She just wanted to be heard.
Sometimes children...
they yell or cry or draw pictures...
I wanna go home.
[music continues]
I can't imagine being stuck down in a well
all alone like that.
How long can you survive?
[melancholic music]
Seven days.
You can survive for seven days.
[music continues]
[Noah. softly] Come on.
[gentle somber music]
[gentle music]
Why don't you just call me sometime?
-Unless you're renting a movie.
-[Rachel chuckles softly]
Call me tomorrow.
And the day after that.
[music fades]
[gentle music]
Rachel?
[Rachel] Mm.
What time is it?
It's either really late or really early.
depending on how you look at it.
Don't you have to be at work?
Not today.
[Aidan] What happened to the girl?
Samara?
Is that her name?
[Rachel] Mm-hm.
Is she still in the dark place?
No.
We set her free.
You helped her?
[Rachel] Yeah.
Why did you do that?
What's wrong. honey?
You weren't supposed to help her.
It's okay. now.
She's not gonna hurt you. She...
[ominous music]
Don't you understand. Rachel?
[whispers] She never sleeps.
[music ends]
[static buzzing]
[buzzing stops]
[low static humming]
[eerie music]
[phone ringing]
Pick up the phone. Noah.
-[ominous music]
-Come on. pick up.
[eerie music]
[phone ringing]
[phone continues ringing]
[dark eerie music]
[static humming]
[phone continues ringing]
[music intensifies]
[tires squealing]
[Rachel] Come on. Noah!
Pick up the goddamn phone!
[horn blaring]
[tires squealing]
[eerie music]
[water trickling]
[phone ringing]
[high-pitched ringing]
[dark musical sting]
[grunts]
[phone continues ringing]
[dramatic musical sting]
[Noah yelps]
[groaning]
[tense unsettling music]
[phone continues ringing]
[music intensifies]
[screams]
[static buzzing]
[brakes squealing]
[dramatic music]
Come on!
[phone ringing]
[music ends]
[ringing stops]
[glass crunching]
[ominous whooshing]
[screaming]
[scream echoing]
[elevator whirring]
[breathing shakily]
[anticipatory music]
[Rachel] Go to your room!
Now!
[music continues]
What do you want?
[screams] What do you want?!
What do you want from me?!
[sobbing]
[crying]
[somber music]
Why not me?
What did I do that he didn't?
[dark music]
[Rachel] She just wanted to be heard.
[low rumbling]
[Samara] He wants me to go away.
My wife was not supposed to have a child!
[Anna] All I ever wanted was you.
[Aidan] Don't you understand. Rachel?
But he doesn't know...
[whispers] She never sleeps.
[Richard] You take one person's tragedy
and force the world to experience it.
spread it like sickness.
[man] You don't wanna hurt anyone.
But I do...
and I'm sorry.
It won't stop.
[low rumbling]
[Rachel] I made a copy.
Push it in.
Play.
Push.
[high-pitched ringing]
-[eerie music]
-It's going to keep going. isn't it?
She'll never stop.
Don't worry. sweetie.
You're gonna be okay.
What about the person we show it to?
What happens to them?
[eerie music continues]
[static buzzing]
[static getting louder]
[intense musical sting]
[static stops]
[mysterious music]
[music continues]
[tense music]
[music intensifies]
[gentle music]
[mysterious music]
[somber music]
[music intensifies]
[music fades. continues]
[dark music]
[anticipatory music]
[music intensifies]
[intense music]
[music fades]
[bright gentle music]
[Samara. softly] ♪ Here we go ♪
♪ The world is spinning ♪
♪ When it stops ♪
♪ It's just beginning ♪
♪ Sun comes up ♪
♪ We live and we cry ♪
♪ Sun goes down ♪
♪ And then we all die ♪